It's the final match
of E-Card.
Ｅカード 最終戦
Kaiji is at his wit's end!
カイジ 絶体絶命
Enforcement
ざわ… ざわ… ざわざわざわ…
You're dead! Your switching of
the cards wasn't successful!
死んだ！お前のわな
すり替えは実らない 殺した
I killed it...
皇帝で！ハハハハ…
...with the Emperor!
Tonegawa.
利根川 俺が蛇に見えたか？
Do you see me as a snake?
You're a snake!
蛇だろうが
I see...
そうか なら… お前が蛇なんだ！
In that case,
you are the snake!
何？
What?
こんな もの言わぬカードを
使っての心理戦は
A psychological battle that uses
ambiguous cards like these...
...is like looking into
a mirror.
鏡をのぞき込むようなもの
相手の心を読んでいるつもりが
You plan to read your
opponent's mind,
but you end up putting
yourself in his position.
自分ならどうするかという
自己への問いかけとなり
Before you know it, you're just
tracing your own thinking...
気付けば ただ自分の心を
なぞっているだけ
つまり 俺が蛇に見えた お前こそ
蛇なんだ！
So if you think I'm a snake,
then you're also one.
それがどうした 見苦しい
So what about it?
How disgraceful.
Just die!
I don't want to hear this!
もう死ね 聞きたくもない
Spending your last moments
crying shamelessly and cursing!
最後のときに ぐずぐずと
醜い泣き言 恨み言など
No, that's not it...
いや そんなんじゃない 礼さ
I'm thanking you.
礼？
Thank me...?
Thank you for being a snake.
蛇で いてくれて ありがとう
疑ってくれて ありがとう
And thank you for
being suspicious of me.
奴隷は ２度刺す！
The Slave strikes again!
くー やった！
Alright!
勝った！勝った！
やった！やった！
すごいっすよ！カイジさん
Alright! He won!
Alright! He really did it!
Kaiji! You did it!
カイジさん やったね！
I didn't expect you to do it!
本当に すごいよ
まさか勝てるなんて
You're incredible!
Incredible! Kaiji!
すごい すごいよ カイジさん！
そんな… そんな ばかな！
This is... this is impossible!
どうして奴隷 どうして？
Why is it the Slave... Why?
Hadn't he switched the cards?
He'd bled on them then...
すり替えたんじゃないのか…
あのとき 血が飛び散る前に！
カイジ… んん… んんっ
Kaiji!
カイジ！
すり替えたんじゃないのか！
Didn't you swap the cards?!
残念だが そうじゃねえのさ
Unfortunately, I didn't.
確かに その時間はあった
Indeed, I had enough time
to do so.
And while I did something similar,
I didn't switch the cards...
そして それに近いことはしたが
すり替えは しなかった
何？
What?
俺がしたのは 血が飛び散る前に
What I did was...
before splattering the blood,
11戦で使った市民と奴隷を
手元に引き寄せ
I moved the Citizen and Slave
cards from the 11th round...
...into my hand.
Then I placed a Citizen card
next to them,
その横に ただ市民を置き
その市民をそのまま手に戻した
and returned the Citizen card
back into my hand.
すり替えもどき それだけ
I pretended to switch
the cards, that's all.
That's impossible!
ばかな…
そんな ばかなことがあるか！
How could such an impossible
thing happen?
What if I had only noticed the
blood, but didn't suspect you?!
わしが血に気付いただけで その後
疑わなかったら どうするんだ！
わしがカードの血を
ただのミスとしか見なかったら
What if I saw the blood as
just a mistake?!
お前は ただ無為に
わしに奴隷の目印だけを与えて
You'd have simply marked out
the Slave for me and died!
死… 死んでいたじゃないか！
Wouldn't you have died?!
Why?! Why?!
どうして？どうして？
どうして お前は…
Why did you...
カイジ… んんん…
Kaiji!
That's simple...
I trusted you!
簡単さ 俺は信頼したんだ
何？信頼？
What? Trust...?
That's right. No matter how much
the director complained about you,
そうさ
そこの会長が どう毒づこうと
I think highly of you.
俺は あんたを買っている
優秀だ それも とびっきり
You're exceptional,
and have been so by far.
There's no way such a man
wouldn't notice the blood first.
そんな男が まず この血に
気付かないはずがない
With your talent,
you'd surely notice it.
気付くさ 優秀なんだから
And you wouldn't just believe
it was a honest mistake.
気付いたら その血をそのまま
単純に信じたりしない
You'd try to read my mind...
and see through my plans.
必ず洞察する 見抜く
こちらの作為を
優秀なんだから
Because you're exceptional,
you'd start to suspect me.
優秀だから 気付いた後に疑うんだ
You'll start to draw your
own conclusions...
そして その洞察は きっと届く
That I had the chance to
switch the cards.
すり替えのチャンスが
あったことに
そこに たどりつけば
俺の疑わしい動きにも気付き
And when you believe that, you'll
detect my suspicious behaviour.
ほくそ笑む このばかめと
You'd think what
a moron I am,
and so you wouldn't
question your own victory.
そうなれば
もう自分の勝ちを疑わない
そりゃそうだ なんせ 今
自分が相手にしてるのは
And why not? After all,
the person opposite you is...
くず… ごみ… 劣等…
Trash, garbage and second-class.
You'd think an outstanding person
like you wouldn't lose.
優秀な自分が
まさか敗れるなんて思わない
You would become arrogant
since you know you're exceptional...
おごる おごるさ 優秀だから
...simply because you've been
winning all the while,
ここまで くずを寄せつけず
勝ち続けてきたんだから！
which sets yourself apart
from the garbage!
And so, the final round of E-Card
comes to an end.
こうして
12戦に及ぶＥカードは終了
カイジは 勝負こそ５勝７敗と
負け越したものの
Though Kaiji recorded
7 defeats and only 5 victories,
due to his double 18 mm victories
in the final two rounds,
ラスト２戦
奴隷での18ミリ勝負の連勝が効き
実質的には勝利で終わる
he emerged as the overall winner.
Kaiji managed to survive!
カイジは生き残り
And he receives his reward!
そして得る
A huge sum of 20.1 million!
大金2010万円！
ハハハハ… すばらしい
This is amazing...
カイジ君が 実に すばらしい
Kaiji, you're really amazing!
それに比べて この男は
とんだ恥さらし 醜態だ
On the other hand, this man
is a complete disgrace!
当然 許されぬ
He'll definitely not
be forgiven.
You will pay
for your mistakes.
してもらうぞ 償いだけは
I'll make sure of that!
きっちりとな
Now then, Kaiji...
さて カイジ君 確か
金を得て終わりではなかったな
I remember the reward wasn't
the end of the deal, right?
ああっ そうだ！利根川
土下座だ！謝ってもらうぞ
That's right!
Tonegawa, kneel down!
I'll want you to apologise Ishida,
Sahara and the rest who died!
死んでいった石田さんや
佐原たちに
分かってないな カイジ君
You don't understand, Kaiji!
What?
Humans will kneel when they
have to in times of need...
人間 いよいよとなれば
頭など いくらでも下げる
問題なのは その行為ではなく
誠意だろう？
The problem doesn't lie with
doing it. It's the sincerity.
腹の底から謝っているか どうかだ
Are they apologising from
the bottom of their hearts?
誠意？
Sincerity...
いくら床に
額をこすりつけようとも
No matter how many
times he kowtows,
腹ん中で 舌を出されていては
if he's mocking you
in his heart,
死んでいった なんとかいう連中も
浮かばれは せんだろう？カイジ君
the dead won't rest
in peace too, right?
Kaiji.
そりゃまあ…
That's true...
I know very well how meaningless
kneeling down can be...
わしは 身にしみているのだ
土下座の無意味さについて
腹の底からな
From the bottom of
my heart!
How about it? Please!
わしは 困ってる人間に
拝み倒されると
I couldn't just ignore those people
who are pleading with me,
Please! Please!
見捨てることができず
次々に金を貸し続けてきたのだ
so I continued to lend
them money.
I wanted to help them...
助けてやりたくてな
だが 結果
煮え湯を飲まされ続けてきた
However, in the end I just ended up
being cheated again and again.
お互いの同意の上で
契約したにも関わらず
They ignore the contracts signed
in agreement by both parties,
いざ返す段になると
平然と踏み倒してくる
and drag their feet when
the time comes for repayment.
Of course they looked apologetic
and kowtowed to me.
無論 表面上は
すまなそうな顔をして
床に額をこすりつけはするが
Please wait another 3 days,
I beg of you!
They thought why didn't this man
forgive them despite their apologies?
どうして これほど謝っているのに
こいつは許してくれないのか
などと 心中 こちらを非難
冷血漢呼ばわりしてくるのだ
They blamed me, and called
me a cold-blooded man.
Don't you think
that's a terrible story?
ひどい話だと思わないか？
当然 そんな連中の わびに
誠意があるはずもない
Of course, those people weren't
sincere in apologising at all.
第一 借金における誠意なんて
In the first place, no matter
how you think about it,
これはもう 誰が考えたって
１つしかないのだ
there's only one way to show your
sincerity towards your debt.
すなわち 何をしてもいいから
期日までに金を返すことだ
In other words,
they are free to do
anything they want,
as long as they repay
the money by the deadline!
それ以外に誠意などない
There can be no other way!
Yes, they can't be sincere
if they don't repay their debt!
そう 金を返さない時点で
やつらに誠意なんてものは ない
To prove that, I added some weight
to the action of kneeling,
その証拠に 土下座に
ちょっとした負荷を加えただけで
which made them unable to
render a satisfactory apology.
もう連中は 満足に謝ることも
できなくなる ヒヒ…
They were originally
able to do so!
本来できるはずなのだ
If they were truly filled
with remorse,
本当にすまないという気持ちで
胸がいっぱいなら
どこであれ 土下座ができる
they'd have been able
to kneel anywhere.
Even if you have to do it
on a metal plate...
たとえそれが 肉焦がし 骨焼く
...that burns the flesh and
roasts the bones!
鉄板の上でもな！
That is what sincerity
is all about...
それでこそ誠意というもの
Right, Tonegawa?
のう？利根川
I don't have to explain
this to you,
お前には
説明するまでもないんだが
but I'll do it just in case.
一応 念のために言っておく
I'll have you lower your head
for at least 10 seconds...
この焼き土下座は
謝罪する側の誠意の証明として
...on this burning plate to show
your sincerity in apologising!
最低10秒は 頭を下げてもらう
10秒のスタートは
額を鉄板に付けた瞬間から
The time will start when your
forehead touches the metal plate.
もし土下座が
10秒に至らない場合は やり直し
In the event that you can't last
10 seconds, you'll do it again.
You'll apologise once more,
もう一度 謝ってもらう
始めっからな
right from the start.
何度でもやる
You'll do it as many times as needed
until you finish the full 10 seconds.
10秒の土下座が達成されるまで
何度でも
The skin and flesh on your
forehead will slowly melt...
それこそ 額の皮も肉も溶け
直接 頭蓋骨を
焼くことになろうともだ
Your skull will also
start to roast...
アハッ
何もそこまでという顔だな
You're wondering why
I'm doing this, aren't you?
しかし こうでなければ いかん
But this is something
that has to be done.
The value of atonement rises along
with the severity of the pain.
謝罪という行為は つらければ
つらいほど その価値を増す
By enduring the pain, one is
able to prove his sincerity.
そのつらさに耐えてこそ
証明できるのだ
誠意らしきものを ハハハハ…
できるはずだ 本当にすまないと
He should be able to do it,
if he's really sorry.
If he's sorry from the bottom
of his heart, he will apologise.
謝りたい気持ちで胸いっぱいなら
謝れる
いや 謝らずには おれんはずだ
No, he can't move on
without apologising.
それが カイジ君の友人たちの
無念を晴らすことになり
Your friends will be able to
rest in peace then.
同時に 恥をかいた わしへの
正当な わびにもなろう
At the same time, he can apologise
to me for bringing me shame.
ハハハハ 当然だ
Such a thing is only natural...
これくらいは当然
誠意とは それほど厳しいのだ
Sincerity is going through
such lengths!
のう 利根川
お前は示せるよな 誠意を
Right, Tonegawa? You'll
show your sincerity, won't you?
Sincerity...
Your true sincerity...
本当の誠意を
フンッ
やはり自分からは できぬかの
おい！
So you can't do it
on your own after all.
Hey!
はっ！準備だ
Yes! Get ready!
わしは実に これが好きでの
Actually, I really like
this contraption!
土下座強制機
The Forced Kneeling
Machine!
やめてくれ！お願いだ！
Please stop this, I beg of you!
必ず返す…
I'll surely repay you!
Those insolent people who
don't repay their debts...
借金を踏み倒す不心得者を
この機械に乗せ
...are forced to kneel down
on top of this machine!
強引に土下座させる
だが ここまで
体勢を作っているにも関わらず
However, if these scoundrels
still refuse to kneel...
...after doing so much to
get them into position,
まだ土下座に至らない不心得者は
強引に誠意を実行させる
they are forced to show
their sincerity.
おとなしくしていれば
焼かれるのは額だけで済むが
If they behave properly,
only the forehead is roasted.
暴れるから 顔中を焼かれ
If they struggle,
the whole face is roasted.
もん絶… 失禁する
They faint and even
wet their pants!
そろそろ やってもらおうかのう
It's about time for you
to do it.
Let's start the Roasting
Kneeling!
スタートだ 焼き土下座
触るな！わしに指一本触れるな！
Don't touch me!
Don't lay a finger on me!
It's alright if I do it myself,
right?!
１人でやれば問題なかろう！
１人で…
I'll do it myself...
ヒヒヒヒ もちろんだ
Of course. That's the most
ideal option.
もちろん
それが いちばん望ましい
ああ しかし 利根川
お前も知ってるように
However, Tonegawa,
as you know,
nobody has been able
to kneel continuously...
この焼き土下座を10秒
自力で やり続けた者は いない
...for 10 seconds
by their own ability.
あまり無理しない方が
身のためだぞ
It's to your benefit
if you don't overdo things...
If you fail, your face will be
roasted numerous times.
失敗すると
何度も顔を焼くことになるぞ
Sizzle, sizzle, sizzle!
Sizzle away!
どけろ その機械をどけろ！
Move aside!
Move away from the machine!
イヒ…
エヘ… エヘ… イヒヒヒ…
利根川…
Tonegawa...
永遠に思える10秒
The 10 seconds felt like
forever...
During those 10 seconds,
a dreadful smell gradually emerged.
あびきょうかん
異臭と 阿鼻叫喚の中 続く10秒
An unending nightmare...
覚めない悪夢
ゆえつ
悪魔の愉悦 地獄
The devil's enjoyment...
An abyss...
ああっ まだ４秒…
It's only been 4 seconds...
利根川… 利根川…
Tonegawa... Tonegawa...
Impossible... What's
with these tears?!
ばかな… 何だ？
何の涙だ くそっ！
Darn it! Darn it!
くそーっ！
In the end, Tonegawa managed to
last 12 seconds on the hot plate.
結局 利根川は この生き地獄を
12秒やりおおし 果てる
やりおおした後は しばらく動けず
患部を冷やし タオルで治療後
He was unable to move
for a while after that,
and had cold towels applied
to his injuries.
He was later able to stand
with some support, and left...
肩を借りながら やっと立ち上がり
退室
In any case, Tonegawa
was able to do it.
しかし 利根川は やりおおした
焼き土下座を！
He was able to perform
the Roasting Kneel!
ハアアア… アヒ… アアア…
間違ってた
I was wrong...
What?
俺は…
間違っていたって 何が？
What do you mean by that?
利根川は本当の敵じゃない
かいらいだ
Tonegawa isn't our real enemy.
He's just a puppet.
あいつも俺たちと同じように
ただ 利用されてきただけ
He was just being made use of,
just like we were.
あの男 会長だ
That man...
The director...
会長を倒さなければ
Ishida and the rest won't be avenged
until I've beaten the director!
石田さんたちの
敵をとったことには ならない
そんな気持ちも分からないでは…
Well... It's not that I don't
understand how you feel...
But we can't do anything
about it...
でも それは
しょうがないっていうか
俺は勝ってねえんだ
勝ってねえ！
I have yet to win!
I haven't won!
そんなこと ないっすよ
十分 勝ってるじゃないですか
That's not the case!
You've won quite a lot, right?
だからこその この金
That's why you have
all that money!
That's just the fee for staging
a performance for the director!
それは 会長のためのショーを
演じた出演料 ギャラだ
ギャラで いいじゃないですか
金は金っすよ 変わりません
What's wrong with it
being a fee?
It's still money.
That fact doesn't change!
カイジさんだって 金のために
闘ってきたんじゃないですか
Didn't you come this far
for money as well, Kaiji?
違う… 金は半分
No! Half of it was
for the money,
俺は金だけでなく 何というか…
but I didn't do it just
for that.
How do I put it...
I wanted to defeat the enemy!
倒したかったんだ 敵を
The enemy...
In other words,
つまり できることなら その金を
I would use that money
if I have the ability...
もう一度 全てを賭けて
I would bet it all once again and
have a face-off with that man.
あの男と…
やめてくださいよ
何言ってるんですか！
Please stop it!
What are you saying?!
この金 もう 奇跡的っていうか
天井ですよ
No matter what, getting this
money is a miracle in itself!
それとも この先 更に勝負して
Or do you mean that you have
a plan to win yet another bet?
勝つ算段っていうか
勝算でもあるんですか？
ない…
No...
じゃあ やめてくださいよ
Then please stop it!
どうせ カイジさんだって
たんまり 借金あるんでしょ？
Besides, you have
a huge debt, don't you?
この金は
それを返して やり直す金
This money is for you
to repay your debts,
and to start all over again!
一か八か勝負する金じゃ
ないでしょ？違いますか？
Am I wrong?
そりゃ そうだけど…
Well, you are right...
That's true.
そうなんだけど… くそっ！
Darn it!
結局 カイジは
しぶしぶ 矛を収める
In the end, Kaiji reluctantly gave
up the idea against his will.
しかたなく
だあっ… うう… ああっ…
ああ カイジさん！タ… タオル！
Kaiji!
Get a towel!
もう ないんすよ さっき
利根川が冷やすのに使って
There's no more left! They were used
to help cool Tonegawa down.
じゃあ ティッシュを大量に！
あっ は はい！
Then go get some tissue!
Right!
ばか！貸せ！
You idiot, pass that to me!
ちょっと
しみるかもしれませんが…
This may hurt a bit...
救急箱を借りてきました
I managed to find
a first-aid box!
カイジの耳の傷… その応急処置…
The bleeding from Kaiji's
wound was finally stopped,
とりあえずの止血…
thanks to the first-aid
treatment.
ちょっと 不格好ですけど…
あの…
It may look a bit odd...
Well...
行きましょう 病院に
耳 今なら くっつきますよ きっと
Let's go to the hospital.
I'm sure they can still
reattach your ear!
ああ… みんな…
Guys...
いろいろ ありがとう
Thank you for everything...
カイジさん…
何言ってんすか
Kaiji.
What are you saying?
This is to be expected!
これくらい当然ですよ
俺たち本当に うれしかったんです
一矢 報いてくれて
We were elated that you
managed to stand up for us!
そうですよ カイジさん
うれしかったんですから
You really did it!
Kaiji, you were great!
すっと しましたよ
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
だから もう帰りましょう
Let's go back, alright?
さあ
Come on.
そのとき
At that point...
引っかかる
Something flashed across
Kaiji's mind!
よぎる… カイジに「何か」！
会長を倒しうる「何か」が
A plan to defeat the director!
Next, Heresy.